<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave&#39;s Notebook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dave&#39;s Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Informal Communications between cars and humans.</title>
      <link>/2020/05/29/informal-communications-between-cars-and-humans./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/29/informal-communications-between-cars-and-humans./</guid>
      <description>There are two things that humans do very well, often without conciously thinking about it. Tool Use and Communication.
Subconcious communication is a topic of special interest to me, because there are a lot of things that human brains do automatically which mine, mostly doesn’t.I have a thing called prosopognasia, an inability to automatically recognise faces. &amp;#8853; To be precise I have a variant of this called prosopamnesia. In brief, there is a specialised bit of brain which does face recognistion and storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topsy</title>
      <link>/2020/05/28/topsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/28/topsy/</guid>
      <description>I have a fascination with Elephants.One of the goals of the daily writing practice is to contribute towards a biography of famous elephants.&amp;#8853; I think it might take a while before I get to that point, so I’ll probably revisit the stories of different elephants a fair bit on the way. This piece is really intended to be a very very brief introduction to Topsy This came about after reading about Topsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early writing</title>
      <link>/2020/05/27/early-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/27/early-writing/</guid>
      <description>I aspired to be a writer when I was younger.
When I was (I think) 7 I won an award for writing. I had written a story for a normal school assignment &amp;#8853; Oddly I can’t remember any of the details of the story.  but one of the teachers &amp;#8853; Mrs McCarthey, I believe.  really liked the story and submitted it as an entry to the South Wales Writing Association.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>