<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dave&#39;s Notebook</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dave&#39;s Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Interface: Connecting Devices</title>
      <link>/2020/06/09/command-interface-connecting-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/09/command-interface-connecting-devices/</guid>
      <description>I have this boat that I live in.I have long had plans to add automation solutions and sensors and all sorts of fun things to it. But I’ve rarely had the time or energy, and also things like floors and walls have generally taken precedence.
We now have quite a few floors &amp;#8853; Also quite a few flaws, but I’m working on that.  and walls, albeit not quite as many as we should have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crows</title>
      <link>/2020/06/08/crows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/08/crows/</guid>
      <description>There are some crows on the island.
A few years ago I came home from the shops with a little snack, a hot cumberland sausage on a stick. I was going to sit on the deck of my boat with a drink and a sausage. I went down into the boat to get some ice and a glass. A crow flapped up on to the mast of the boat moored next to mine, and I heard a caw-caw noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Improvisational Doughnuts</title>
      <link>/2020/06/07/recipe-improvisational-doughnuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/07/recipe-improvisational-doughnuts/</guid>
      <description>I’m not a great cook. I would say that I am broadly competent. I do however consider myself to be a reasonably good solver of problems. So in that spirit I’m going to write this whilst I am cooking this recipe. &amp;#8853; Or at least whilst I try and invent a suitable recipe  This may turn out to be a complete disaster. But on the principle that you should report all your trials (and not just the succesful ones) I’m going to write as I cook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drabble: Idempotence</title>
      <link>/2020/06/06/drabble-idempotence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/06/drabble-idempotence/</guid>
      <description>A drabble is a short piece of fiction 100 words in length. This is not quite that, It’s an attempt to explain a concept in exactly 100 words. This is my first go writing to this particular format, but if you’d like to see it done well (and to learn some philosophy at the same time) have a look at these.
An idempotent function is one which if run multiple times produces the same output as if it were run only once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse Experiments</title>
      <link>/2020/06/04/timelapse-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/04/timelapse-experiments/</guid>
      <description>I found an old camera when I was tidying up. So I decided to try and find a use for it.
The camera is a TP-Link NC250. It’s an end of life product so is unsupported.The first step was to plug it in and see if it would connect. The first experiment yielded very little. It was connecting via an extension router. I tried both WPS and ethernet, but the TPCamera app reported “Can’t Find Camera”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperloop (But Good)</title>
      <link>/2020/06/03/hyperloop-but-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/03/hyperloop-but-good/</guid>
      <description>Hyperloop really annoys me. It annoys me for a number of reasons, but the first is that I’m writing about Hyperloop style systems by using the name Hyperloop.
The idea of firing a capsule through a low pressure tube using magnetic propulsion is not a new idea. It’s easily a hundred years old. But because someone who’s only skill is to be rich and to not know what they’re doing &amp;#8853; This is a skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the Gears and Cogs</title>
      <link>/2020/06/02/all-the-gears-and-cogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/02/all-the-gears-and-cogs/</guid>
      <description>This is planned to be a brief note on the things I used to make this website.
I needed to make a website for someone to post their daily writing. &amp;#8853; It turned out that this daily writing habit was having a lot of benefits for them, so I copied it  So, my first instinct was of course, to load up R Studio and start there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Colours of Butterflies</title>
      <link>/2020/06/01/the-colours-of-butterflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/01/the-colours-of-butterflies/</guid>
      <description>I was working on a more complicated post about timetable data formats, but I’ve parked it for now because the child needed to be taken out to the woods to play. As we were watching the clouds of billions of tiny flies lit up by the setting sun and pretending to be galaxies I asked the child what I should write about instead. They said “Butterflies”.
So here is a short post about butterflies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate Cinderella Stories</title>
      <link>/2020/05/31/alternate-cinderella-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/31/alternate-cinderella-stories/</guid>
      <description>I was just watching the new(ish) Cinderella film (Because I have a small child who was busy ignoring it). It was pretty good. Though true to the original animated one Cinderella has basically zero agency and things just happen to her. &amp;#8853; I liked the goose though.  It made me think of some alternate takes on the story.
Magic as a weapon of social privilege.Cinderella marries Prince Charming &amp;#8853; He’s lucky he’s a prince, with a name like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes in R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/30/recipes-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/30/recipes-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t used much R Markdown before. I briefly played about with it for producing self reporting models, but the transport consulting world likes what it likes. &amp;#8853; and what they like is excel models and word reports  I haven’t had the time to explore further. So this writing site is my main experiment area for R Markdown.
I’m going to look into an R Markdown solution for my recipes problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informal Communications Between Cars and Humans</title>
      <link>/2020/05/29/informal-communications-between-cars-and-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/29/informal-communications-between-cars-and-humans/</guid>
      <description>There are two things that humans do very well, often without conciously thinking about it. Tool Use and Communication.
Subconcious communication is a topic of special interest to me, because there are a lot of things that human brains do automatically which mine, mostly doesn’t.I have a thing called prosopognasia, an inability to automatically recognise faces. &amp;#8853; To be precise I have a variant of this called prosopamnesia. In brief, there is a specialised bit of brain which does face recognistion and storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topsy</title>
      <link>/2020/05/28/topsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/28/topsy/</guid>
      <description>I have a fascination with Elephants.One of the goals of the daily writing practice is to contribute towards a biography of famous elephants.&amp;#8853; I think it might take a while before I get to that point, so I’ll probably revisit the stories of different elephants a fair bit on the way. This piece is really intended to be a very very brief introduction to Topsy This came about after reading about Topsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early writing</title>
      <link>/2020/05/27/early-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/27/early-writing/</guid>
      <description>I aspired to be a writer when I was younger.
When I was (I think) 7 I won an award for writing. I had written a story for a normal school assignment &amp;#8853; Oddly I can’t remember any of the details of the story.  but one of the teachers &amp;#8853; Mrs McCarthey, I believe.  really liked the story and submitted it as an entry to the South Wales Writing Association.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>