<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dave&#39;s Notebook</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dave&#39;s Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Colours of Butterflies</title>
      <link>/2020/06/01/the-colours-of-butterflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/01/the-colours-of-butterflies/</guid>
      <description>I was working on a more complicated post about timetable data formats, but I’ve parked it for now because the child needed to be taken out to the woods to play. As we were watching the clouds of billions of tiny flies lit up by the setting sun and pretending to be galaxies I asked the child what I should write about instead. They said “Butterflies”.
So here is a short post about butterflies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate Cinderella Stories</title>
      <link>/2020/05/31/alternate-cinderella-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/31/alternate-cinderella-stories/</guid>
      <description>I was just watching the new(ish) Cindarella film (Because I have a small child who was busy ignoring it). It was pretty good. Though true to the original animated one Cinderella has basically zero agency and things just happen to her. &amp;#8853; I liked the goose though.  It made me think of some alternate takes on the story.
Magic as a weapon of social privilege.Cinderella marries Prince Charming &amp;#8853; He’s lucky he’s a prince, with a name like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes in R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/30/recipes-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/30/recipes-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t used much R Markdown before. I briefly played about with it for producing self reporting models, but the transport consulting world likes what it likes. &amp;#8853; and what they like is excel models and word reports  I haven’t had the time to explore further. So this writing site is my main experiment area for R Markdown.
I’m going to look into an R Markdown solution for my recipes problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informal Communications Between Cars and Humans</title>
      <link>/2020/05/29/informal-communications-between-cars-and-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/29/informal-communications-between-cars-and-humans/</guid>
      <description>There are two things that humans do very well, often without conciously thinking about it. Tool Use and Communication.
Subconcious communication is a topic of special interest to me, because there are a lot of things that human brains do automatically which mine, mostly doesn’t.I have a thing called prosopognasia, an inability to automatically recognise faces. &amp;#8853; To be precise I have a variant of this called prosopamnesia. In brief, there is a specialised bit of brain which does face recognistion and storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topsy</title>
      <link>/2020/05/28/topsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/28/topsy/</guid>
      <description>I have a fascination with Elephants.One of the goals of the daily writing practice is to contribute towards a biography of famous elephants.&amp;#8853; I think it might take a while before I get to that point, so I’ll probably revisit the stories of different elephants a fair bit on the way. This piece is really intended to be a very very brief introduction to Topsy This came about after reading about Topsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early writing</title>
      <link>/2020/05/27/early-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/27/early-writing/</guid>
      <description>I aspired to be a writer when I was younger.
When I was (I think) 7 I won an award for writing. I had written a story for a normal school assignment &amp;#8853; Oddly I can’t remember any of the details of the story.  but one of the teachers &amp;#8853; Mrs McCarthey, I believe.  really liked the story and submitted it as an entry to the South Wales Writing Association.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>