<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vagary on Dave&#39;s Notebook</title>
    <link>/series/vagary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vagary on Dave&#39;s Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/series/vagary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Interface: Further interfaces</title>
      <link>/2020/06/10/command-interface-further-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/10/command-interface-further-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Today’s project was to try and enhance the very basic interface I built yesterday.
HomeFirst I built a frontpage to let me navigate around the application. It currently looks like this:
It works quite nicely on a full screen touch panel.
Since it’s running in shiny it automatically exists as a server on the network.I’ve given it a fixed port to run on so that you can access it from any device on the boat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Interface: Simple Interface Experiment</title>
      <link>/2020/06/10/command-interface-simple-interface-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/10/command-interface-simple-interface-experiment/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing around with the idea of bringing together a bunch of my boat’s information and control systems into one slightly more cohesive control console.
I put a little bit of time into putting together an appropriate console to test the pump control. &amp;#8853; The control system for the pump is hopefully only a stopgap solution. It should be possible to control all the systems without having to go out to the internet and back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Interface: Connecting Devices</title>
      <link>/2020/06/09/command-interface-connecting-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/09/command-interface-connecting-devices/</guid>
      <description>I have this boat that I live in.I have long had plans to add automation solutions and sensors and all sorts of fun things to it. But I’ve rarely had the time or energy, and also things like floors and walls have generally taken precedence.
We now have quite a few floors &amp;#8853; Also quite a few flaws, but I’m working on that.  and walls, albeit not quite as many as we should have.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>